John W. Warner papers MSS 10191
University of Virginia, Special Collections Dept.
John W. Warner papers
1967-2009
University of Virginia, Special Collections Dept.
Warner, John W., 1927-
MSS 10191
752 Cubic Feet Majority of materials in cubic foot boxes, also a few document boxes, and oversize folders.
Biographical / Historical
John William Warner (born February 18, 1927) is an American Republican politician who served as Secretary of the Navy from 1972 to 1974 and as a five-term United States Senator from Virginia from January 2, 1979, to January 3, 2009. He did not seek reelection in 2008 and has rejoined the law firm of Hogan & Hartson, where he worked before joining the Department of Defense.
He grew up in Washington D.C. and joined the Navy shortly after graduating from high school, leaving as a Petty Officer 3rd Class. He then did his undergraduate studies at Washington and Lee University and began post-graduate studies at University of Virginia Law School.
With the outbreak of the Korean War in 1950, Warner joined the Marine Corps, first in active duty and then as a reserve, finally earning the rank of Captain. He resumed his studies at George Washington University and received his law degree in 1953.
He has been married three times. His first marriage was to Catherine Conover Mellon in 1957; they divorced in 1973. He was married to actress Elizabeth Taylor in 1976; they divorced in 1982. Since 2003, he has been married to Jeanne Vander Myde. He has three children, all from his first marriage.
In 1987, he was one of few Republicans to reject the nomination of Robert Bork to the Supreme Court. He would later break with Virginia Republicans, refusing to support the campaigns of Mike Farris and Oliver North. In 1996, he was one of ten Republican Senators voting against the charge of perjury in the attempted impechment of President Bill Clinton.
His committee memberships included the Environment and Public Works Committee, the Committee on the Armed Services, the Committee on Homeland Security and Government Affairs, the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Banking, Housing and Urban Affairs.
Scope and Content note
This collection includes general and constituent correspondence, office files, speeches, appointment books, photographs, scrapbooks, and clippings documenting Senator Warner's life and career.
Acquisition information
This collection has come to the Small Library in multiple accession over the years beginning in 1974. Accessions include: MSS #10191, MSS #10191-b, MSS #10191-c through -n, MSS #10191-e, MSS #10191-o, MSS #10191-p through -z, MSS #10191-ab through -az, MSS #10191-ba through -bp, MSS #-bq, Mss #10191-br, MSS #10191-bs, MSS #10191-bt, MSS #10191-bu, MSS #10191-bv, MSS #10191-bw, MSS #10191-bx, MSS #10191-by, MSS #10191-bz, MSS #10191-cb
Arrangement
The series have been placed roughly in the order of their arrival to the repository.
Correspondence; Photographs.; Legislators -- United States; Political letter writing -- United States; United States -- Politics and government -- 1989-1993; United States -- Politics and government -- 1993-2001.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1977-1981.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1981-1989.; Warner, John W., 1927-.
- John W. Warner papers, 1972-1976; MSS #10191; 10750 items (Mss 10191, Box MSS 10191 Box 1, Box MSS 10191 Box 2, Box MSS 10191 Box 3, Box MSS 10191 Box 4, Box MSS 10191 Box 5, Box MSS 10191 Box 6, Box MSS 10191 Box 7, Box MSS 10191 Box 8, Box MSS 10191 Box 9, Box MSS 10191 Box 10, Box MSS 10191 Box 11, Box MSS 10191 Box 12, Box MSS 10191 Box 13, Box MSS 10191 Box 14, Box MSS 10191 Box 15, Box MSS 10191 Box 16, Box MSS 10191 Box 17, Box MSS 10191 Box 18, Box MSS 10191 Box 19, Box MSS 10191 Box 20, Box MSS 10191 Box 21, Box MSS 10191 Box 22, Box MSS 10191 Box 23, Box MSS 10191 Box 24, Box MSS 10191 Box 25, Box MSS 10191 Box 26, Box MSS 10191 Box 27, Box MSS 10191 Box 28, Box MSS 10191 Box 29, Box MSS 10191 Box 30, Box MSS 10191 Box 31, Box MSS 10191 Box 32, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box A, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box B, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box 1, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box 2, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box 3, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box 4, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box 5, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box 6, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box 7, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box 8, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box 9, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box 10, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box 11, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box 12, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box 13, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box 14, Box MSS 10191 Indexes Box 17)
  Access Restrictions
  This collection is available for use.
  Scope and Content Information
  The collection contains correspondence, scrapbooks, photograph album, facsimiles of historic documents, a three volume comprehensive calendar of Bicentennial events, and printed material generated by Senator Warner as administrator of the American Revolution Bicentennial Administration.
  Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Senator Warner, 24 August 1974.
  Administrative papers.; American Revolution Bicentennial, 1976.; Photograph albums.; Scrapbooks.; United States, History, Centennial celebrations, etc.; American Revolution Bicentennial Administration.; Warner, John W., 1927-.
- Warner papers from his service as administrator of the American Revolution Bicentennial Administration (-b), 1967-1976; MSS #10191_b; 1 Cubic Feet 2 document boxes (Box MSS 10191-b Box 1, Box MSS 10191-b Box 2)
  This series is open for use.
  The papers contain the resolutions, motions, and actions of the American Revolution Bicentennial Commission, 1967-1973, (the ARBA parent) and of its executive committee; a briefing book of basic data about the ARBA; clippings compiled to illustrate media reaction to Bicentennial events, and Congressional acts about the Bicentennial.
  Also included are documents identifying ARBA themes and priorities, describing international participation, and listing events, listings of important events of the American Revolution and in American history compiled by Sidney Hart, and a scrapbook of projected Bicentennial celebrations at Independence National Historic Park.
  Reproduction Information
  In part: photocopies.
  Gift, Senator Warner, U. S. Senate, 6239 Dirksen Senate Office Building, Washington, D.C. 20510, 1982 June 9.
  Administrative papers.; American Revolution Bicentennial, 1976.; Clippings.; Independence National Historical Park (Philadelphia, Pa.).; Resolutions.; Scrapbooks.; American Revolution Bicentennial Administration.; Hart, Sidney, compiler.
- John W. Warner papers (-c to -n), 1979-1985; MSS #10191_c through 10191_n; 238 Reels Microfilm reels are housed in cubic foot boxes. (Mss 10191-c, -d, -f--- -n, Mss 10191-c, -d, -f-- -n)
  These accessions contain microfilms of Senator Warner's incoming constituent correspondence and attached work sheets coded for computer generated replies, an item or form letter master book containing the replies, and various name indexes and weekly indexes to the correspondence together with some press clippings and indexes.
  10191-c: Gift, Senator Warner, 1982 August 25.
  10191-d: Gift, Senator Warner through director of correspondence Martha L. Spenger, 1983 August 12.
  10191-e: Gift, Senator Warner through director of correspondence Martha L. Spenger, 1983 September 29.
  10191-f (reels 103, 114-116): Gift, Senator Warner through director of correspondence Martha L. Spenger, 1983 October 17.
  10191-g (reels 145-161): Gift, Senator Warner through director of correspondence Martha L. Spenger, 1984 January 31.
  10191-h: Gift, Senator Warner through director of correspondence Martha L. Spenger, 1984 March 29.
  10191-i (reels 164-169): Gift, Senator Warner, 1984 April 17.
  10191-j: Gift, Senator Warner, 1984 June 26.
  10191-k (reels 180-186): Gift, Senator Warner, 1984 August 20.
  10191-l (reels 177-179): Gift, Senator Warner, 1984 November 12.
  10191-m (reels 187-194): Gift, Senator Warner, 1985 February 6.
  10191-n: Gift, Senator Warner, 1985 April 23.
  Legislators -- United States; Mail preparation.; Political letter writing, United States.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1977-1981.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1981-1989.; United States, Congress, Senate, Constituent communications.; United States, Congress, Senate, Records and correspondence.
- John W. Warner item books (-e), 1979-1985; MSS #10191_e; 4 Cubic Feet 16 volumes
  The collection consists of master copies of form letters used by Warner's office staff to respond to incoming correspondence. The books are to be used in conjunction with the microfilm as no paper copies of outgoing correspondence were kept.
  Gift, Senator Warner through director of correspondence Martha L. Spenger, 29 1983 September 1983.
- John W. Warner's Senatorial campaign news clippings (-o), 1984; MSS #10191_o; 3 Cubic Feet 6 document boxes
  This collection is open for use.
  Acquisition Information
  This collection was given by Senator Warner on 13 May 1985.
  The collection contains clippings of news stories and editorials mostly from Warner's campaign against Edythe Harrison with about 100 items of correspondence, chiefly by staff press aides.
  Topics include arms control, avian flu, the Chesapeake Bay, coal mining and shipping and the coal slurry pipeline, defense, the appointment of judges, a Middle Eastern trip, Newport News shipyard, the Republican National Convention, the Virginia Gubernatorial election, the Virginia Congressional delegation, Charles Robb and Paul Trible.
  Arrangement
  These items are arranged alphabetically.
  Arms control.; Avian influenza.; Chesapeake Bay (Md. and Va.).; Coal mines and mining.; Coal slurry pipelines.; Governors, Virginia, Election, 1985.; Judges, Selection and appointment.; Legislators, Virginia.; Middle East, Description and travel.; Presidents, United States, Election, 1984.; United States, Defenses.; Water, Pollution, Law and legislation.
  - Airports (Box 1)
  - Arms Control (Box 1)
  - Avian Flu (Box 1)
  - Black Lung (Box 1)
  - Budget, empty folder (Box 1)
  - Campaign- September (Box 1)
  - Campaign- October, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Campaign- November, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Campaign- December (Box 2)
  - Campaign- Warner Support Items, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Campaign Clippings, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Campaign- Editorials (Box 4)
  - Campaign- Post Election (Box 4)
  - Chesapeake Bay (Box 4)
  - Coal (Box 4)
  - Coal Slurry Pipeline (Box 4)
  - Confidence Building Measures (Box 4)
  - Congressional Races (Box 4)
  - Constituents (Box 4)
  - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - Defense (Box 5)
  - Defense- Star Wars (Box 5)
  - High Technology Center- Northern Virginia (Box 5)
  - Judges (Box 5)
  - Middle East Trip (Box 5)
  - NEAL-SURA (Box 5)
  - Newport News Shipbuilding (Box 5)
  - Ratings and Votes (Box 5)
  - Republican Convention (Box 5)
  - Robb, Charles (Box 5)
  - Senate Election Organization (Box 5)
  - Speeches and Appearances (Box 5)
  - Trible, Paul (Box 5)
  - Virginia (Box 6)
  - Virginia Congressional Delegation (Box 6)
  - Virginia Guberatorial Electino (Box 6)
  - Warner Personal (Box 6)
  - Warner/Harrison Debate (Box 6)
  - Water Projects (Box 6)
- John W. Warner papers (-p to -z), 1985-1986; MSS #10191_p through 10191_z; 84 Reels Microfilm reels are housed in cubic foot boxes.
  These accessions contain microfilms of Senator Warner's incoming constituent correspondence and attached work sheets coded for computer generated replies, changes and additions to the form letter master book containing the replies, and the name file index for 1985.
  10191-p (reels 196-207): Gift, Senator Warner, 1985 May 10.
  10191-q (reels 208-218): Gift, Senator Warner, 1985 May 28.
  10191-r (reels 195, 219-226): Gift, Senator Warner, 1985 November 1.
  10191-s (reels 228-235): Gift, Senator Warner, 1985 November 1.
  10191-t: Gift, Senator Warner, 1985 December 30.
  10191-u: Gift, Senator Warner, 1986 April 16.
  10191-v (reels 245-252): Gift, Senator Warner, 1986 June 4.
  10191-w (reels 253-258): Gift, Senator Warner, 1986 July 17.
  10191-x (reels 259-264): Gift, Senator Warner, 1986 August 11.
  10191-y (reels 265, 266): Gift, Senator Warner, 1986 October 14.
  10191-z (reels 267-274): Gift, Senator Warner, 1986 December 3.
  Legislators -- United States; Mail preparation.; Microfilm.; Political letter writing, United States.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1981-1989.; United States, Congress, Senate, Constituent communications.; United States, Congress, Senate, Records and correspondence.
- John W. Warner papers (-ab to -az), 1979-1993; MSS #10191_ab_az; 215 Reels Microfilm reels in cubic foot boxes.
  These accessions contain additional microfilms of Senator Warner's incoming constituent correspondence and attached work sheets coded for computer generated replies; additions to the form letter master book containing the replies; and the 1988, 1989, 1990, and 1991 name indexes.
  Microfilm.
  10191-ab: Gift, Senator Warner, 421 Russell Senate Office Building, Washington, D. C. 20515, 1987 March 3.
  10191-ac (reels #275-284): Gift, Senator Warner, 1987 March 30.
  10191-ad: Gift, Senator Warner, 1987 June 10.
  10191-ae (reels #286-297): Gift, Senator Warner, 1987 October 5.
  10191-af (reels #298-305): Gift, Senator Warner, 1987 December 7.
  10191-ag (reels #306-307): Gift, Senator Warner, 1988 February 10.
  10191-ah (reels #1-4, 308-316): Gift, Senator Warner, 1988 February 24.
  10191-ai (reels #317-326): Gift, Senator Warner, 1988 June 20.
  10191-aj (reels #328-333): Gift, Senator Warner, 1988 August 9.
  10191-ak (reels #334-341): Gift, Senator Warner, 1989 January 8.
  10191-al (reels #342-350): Gift, Senator Warner, 1989 May 2.
  10191-am (reels #351-357): Gift, Senator Warner, 1989 August 1.
  10191-an (reels #358-367): Gift, Senator Warner, 1989 October 4.
  10191-ao: Gift, Senator Warner, 1989 December 4.
  10191-ap (reels #368-375): Gift, Senator Warner, 1990 February 16.
  10191-aq (reels #376-383): Gift, Senator Warner, 1990 April 4.
  10191-ar (reels #384-391): Gift, Senator Warner, 1990 June 25.
  10191-as (reels #392-399): Gift, Senator Warner, 1990 October 22.
  10191-at: Gift, Senator Warner, 1991 January 10.
  10191-au (reels #1-6, 400-419): Gift, Senator Warner, 1991 May 28.
  10191-av (reels #1-5, 420-436): Gift, Senator Warner, 1991 November 11.
  10191-aw (reels #435-445): Gift, Senator Warner, 1992 January 14.
  10191-ax (reels #453-459): Gift, Senator Warner, 1992 July 1.
  10191-ay (reels #1-4, 446-452, 460-466): Gift, Senator Warner, 1992 December 1.
  10191-az (reels #467-475, 472-b): Gift, Senator Warner, 1993 April 12.
  Legislators -- United States; Mail preparation.; Political letter writing, United States.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1981-1989.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1989-1993; United States, Congress, Senate, Constituent communications.
- John W. Warner papers (-ba to -bp), 1993-1999; MSS #10191_ba_bp; 299 Reels Microfilm reels are housed in cubic foot boxes.
  These accessions contain additional microfilms of Senator Warner's incoming constituent correspondence and attached work sheets coded for computer generated replies; and additions to the form letter master book containing the replies.
  10191-ba (reels #476-478): Gift, Senator Warner, 421 Russell Senate Office Building, Washington, D.C. 20510, 1993 May 28.
  10191-bb (reels #487-507): Gift, Senator Warner, 1993 August 23.
  10191-bc (reels #511-518): Gift, Senator Warner, 1994 January 13.
  10191-bd (reels #519-526): Gift, Senator Warner, 1994 February 7.
  10191-be (reels #527-534): Gift, Senator Warner, 1994 March 3.
  10191-bf (reels #535-544): Gift, Senator Warner, 1994 June 24.
  10191-bg (reels #545-553): Gift, Senator Warner, 1994 August 10.
  10191-bh (reels #508-510, 554-566A): Gift, Senator Warner, 1994 October 25.
  10191-bi (reels #570-577): Gift, Senator Warner, 1995 January 11.
  10191-bj (reels #578-584): Gift, Senator Warner, 1995 May 15.
  10191-bk (reels #585-593): Gift, Senator Warner, 1995 July 5.
  10191-bl (reels #596-602): Gift, Senator Warner, 1995 September 5.
  10191-bm (reels #613-641, 643-697): Gift, Senator Warner, 1998 November 27.
  10191-bn (reels #698-726): Gift, Senator Warner, 1999 September 22.
  10191-bo (reels #1, 2, 162, 567-569, 603-612, 642, 728-744): Gift, Senator Warner, 2000 January 26.
  10191-bp (reels #755-772): Gift, Senator Warner, 2000 September 5.
  Legislators -- United States; Mail preparation.; Political letter writing, United States.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1989-1993; United States -- Politics and government -- 1993-2001.; United States, Congress, Senate, Constituent communications.; United States, Congress, Senate, Records and correspondence.
- Senator Warner papers (-bq), 2000 November 27-2001 August 28; MSS #10191_bq; 33 Reels Microfilm reels housed in cubic foot boxes.
  These accessions contain additional microfilms of Senator Warner's incoming constituent correspondence; and additions to the form letter master book containing the replies.
  Gift, Senator Warner, 421 Russell Senate Office Building, Washington, D.C. 20510, 2002 February 13, 20.
  Other Descriptive Data
  Cartridges 797-829 :Series G: January 5, 2001-August 28, 2001. Series S: November 27, 2000 -July 16, 2001.
  Legislators -- United States; Letters (Correspondence).; Mail preparation.; Political letter writing, United States.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1993-2001.; United States, Congress, Senate, Constituent communications.; United States, Congress, Senate, Records and correspondence.
- Senator Warner papers (-br), 2002 April 3-2003 June 12; MSS #10191_br; 20 Reels Microfilm reels housed in cubic foot boxes.; 3 compact discs (Disk 1898-000, Disk 1901-000, Disk 1902-000)
  These accessions contain additional microfilms and compact discs of Senator Warner's incoming constituent correspondence.
  Gift, Senator Warner, 421 Russell Senate Office Building, Washington, D.C. 20510, 2002 February 13,20.
  Cartridges 855-874 :Series G: April 3, 2002 - October 7, 2002 and compact discs 1-3 October 8, 2002 - June 12, 2003.
  Legislators -- United States; Letters (Correspondence).; Mail preparation.; Political letter writing, United States.; United States -- Politics and government -- 2001-2009; United States, Congress, Senate, Constituent communications.; United States, Congress, Senate, Records and correspondence.
- Senator Warner papers (-bs), 2001 October-2004 February; MSS #10191_bs; 14 compact discs (Disk 1899-000, Disk 1900-000, Disk 1903-000, Disk 1904-000, Disk 1905-000, Disk 1906-000, Disk 1907-000, Disk 1908-000, Disk 1909-000, Disk 1931-000, Disk 1932-000, Disk 1933-000, Disk 1934-000, Disk 1935-000)
  Series is open for use.
  These accessions contain additional compact discs of Senator Warner's constituent correspondence.
  Gift, Senator Warner, 421 Russell Senate Office Building, Washington, D.C. 20510, 2004 April 5.
  Compact discs Series G: October 2, 2001-July 3, 2003 and Series S: December 11, 2002-February 24, 2004.
- Senator Warner papers (-bt), 2003-2004; MSS #10191_bt; 7 compact discs (Disk 1910-000, Disk 1911-000, Disk 1912-000, Disk 1913-000, Disk 1914-000, Disk 1915-000, Disk 1916-000, Disk 1917-000, Disk 1918-000, Disk 1919-000, Disk 1920-000, Disk 1936-000, Disk 1937-000)
  Gift, Senator Warner, 421 Russell Senate Office Building, Washington, D.C. 20510, 2005 February 15.
  compact discs Series G: July 8, 2003 -September 1, 2004 and Series S: February 9, 2004 - July 14, 2004.
- Senator Warner papers (-bu), 2003 July-2005 October; MSS #10191_bu; 14 compact discs
  Gift, Senator Warner, 421 Russell Senate Office Building, Washington, D.C. 20510, 2005 February 15, October 28.
  compact discs Series G: July 8, 2003 - October 3, 2005 and Series S: February 9, 2004 - July 29 2005.
- Senator John W. Warner papers (-bv), 2005 Nov.18-2006 Aug.16; MSS #10191_bv; 5 compact discs (Disk 1921-000, Disk 1922-000, Disk 1923-000, Disk 1924-000, Disk 1938-000)
  Additions to Senator Warner's constituent correspondence.
  Gift, Senator Warner, 225 Russell Senate Office Building, Washington, D.C. 20510, 202-224-2023, 2006 Oct. 28.
  compact discs Series G: Nov.18, 2005-Aug.16, 2006 and Series S Feb. 14, 2006-May 31, 2006.
- Senator John W. Warner papers (-bw), June 6-2006 December 8; MSS #10191_bw; 4 compact discs (Disk 1925-000, Disk 1926-000, Disk 1939-000, Disk 1940-000)
  Gift, Senator Warner, 225 Russell Senate Office Building, Washington, D.C. 20510, 202-224-2023, 2007 January 26.
  compact discs Series G: Aug. 17, 2006-Dec.8, 2006 and Series S: June 6, 2006-Dec. 5, 2006.
- Senator John W. Warner papers (-bx), 2006 December 6-2007 September 20; MSS #10191_bx; 7 compact discs (Disk 1927-000, Disk 1928-000, Disk 1929-000, Disk 1930-000)
  Gift, Senator Warner, 225 Russell Senate Office Building, Washington, D.C. 20510, 202-224-2023, 2007 December 5.
  compact discs Series G:Dec. 6, 2006-Mar.19, 2007, Dec. 11, 2006-Apr. 26, 2007, Apr. 27, 2007-Sep. 28, 2007 and Series S Mar. 2, 2007-Sep. 20, 2007.
- John Warner papers (-by accession), 1970-2007; MSS 10191_by; 713 Cubic Feet Cubic foot boxes; This collection consists of 712 cubic foot boxes.
  Gift of John Warner 24 February 2009.
  Selected Members of Senator Warner's Staff
  Angela Stewart Legislative council for Sen. Warner from 2006 to 2008.
  Ann Loomis Sen. Warner's Chief of Staff from Oct. 2000 to June 2007.
  Anna Reilly Sen. Warner's director of scheduling.
  Awilda Euill Sen. Warner's system administrator from 2000 to 2009.
  Carter Cornick III Sen. Warner's Director of Communications from 2000 to 2002; from 2007 to 2009, he was Sen. Warner's Chief of Staff; he also served as Communications Director for the Senate Armed Services Committee.
  Chelsea Henderson Maxwell Subcommittee Staff Director, Senate Environment and Public Works Committee, Private Sector and Consumer Solutions to Global Warming and Wildlife Protection Subcommittee for Sen. Warner from 2007 to 2009. She has since divorced and goes by her maiden name.
  Chris Yianilos Served many positions under Sen. Warner from Oct. 2000 to Jan. 2009. His last title was Deputy Chief of Staff / Legislative Director.
  Conrad Schatte One of Sen. Warner's legislative assistants from 2002 to 2007.
  Cord Sterling Sen. Warner's Military Legislative Assistant from Feb. 1, 2003 to June 30, 2006.
  Dorienne Steeves Sen. Warner's executive assistant from 2000 to 2009.
  Geoff Schwartzmann Sen. Warner's deputy press secretary from 2000 to 2002.
  Hughes Bates One of Sen. Warner's legislative assistants from 2004 to 2008.
  James Kadtke One of Sen. Warner's legislative assistants from 2004 to 2005.
  Jennifer Cave One of Sen. Warner's legislative assistants from 2001 to 2009.
  John Frierson Sen. Warner's senior legislative assistant from 2001 to 2009.
  Jon Rogers One of Sen. Warner's legislative assistants from 2004 to 2008.
  Kaitlan S. Deal Legislative correspondent for Sen. Warner from 2007 to 2009.
  Kristen Fallon Legislative aide for Sen. Warner from 2007 to 2009.
  Mary Holloway Legislative correspondant for Sen. Warner from 2006 to 2009.
  Patty Kennedy Caseworker for Sen. Warner from 2000 to 2009.
  Remmel Dickinson Member of Sen. Warner's staff from 1979 to 1997.
  Sam Zega Legislative aide for Sen. Warner from 2004 to 2009.
  Sandy Luff Deputy Legislative Director and National Security Adviser for Sen. Warner from 2006 to 2008.
  Shari Gruenwald Sen. Warner's legislative co-ordinator from 2000 to 2009.
  Stuart Verdery Sen. Warner's legislative council in 1996, as well as serving the same role to the Senate Rules and Administration Committee.
  Susan Berry Director of Constituent Services for Sen. Warner from 2000 to 2006.
  Susan Magill Served as Sen. Warner's Chief of Staff, from 1988 to 2006; as Legislative Director 1967 from 1987; and as Asst. Legislative Director 1983-1984.